You know, what I do is write for children,
كما تعلمون ان ما اقوم به هو الكتابه للاطفال,
and I'm probably America's
وانا على الارجح في امريكا
most widely read children's author, in fact.
المؤلف الاكثر قراءة من الاطفال,في الحقيقة
And I always tell people
وكما اخبر الناس دائما
that I don't want to show up looking like a scientist.
انني لا احب الظهور في صورة عالم
You can have me as a farmer, or in leathers,
يمكنك مشاهدتي كمزارع , او في ملابس جلدية,
and no one has ever chose farmer.
ولم يقم اي احد باختيار المزارع على الاطلاق
I'm here today to talk to you
انا هنا اليوم للحديث اليكم
about circles and epiphanies.
عن الدوائر وادراك الحقائق.
And you know, an epiphany
وكما تعلمون ,ادراك الحقيقة
is usually something you find that you dropped someplace.
هو غالبا ان تجد شيئا كنت قد اسقطته في مكان ما.
You've just got to go around the block
يتوجب عليك ان تدور حول الحائط
to see it as an epiphany.
لتراه كحقيقة مدركة
That's a painting of a circle.
ذلك رسم لدائرة
A friend of mine did that -- Richard Bollingbroke.
صديق لي فعل ذلك-- ريتشارد بولينجبروك.
It's the kind of complicated circle
كانت ذلك النوع من الدوائر المعقدة
that I'm going to tell you about.
وهو ما سوف اخبركم عنه.
My circle began back in the '60s
دائرتي تبدا في الستينات
in high school in Stow, Ohio
في المدرسة الثانوية في ستو , اوهيو
where I was the class queer.
حيث كنت انا الطالب الغريب الاطوار في الفصل.
I was the guy beaten up bloody
كنت ذلك الشاب الذي ضُرب بدموية
every week in the boys' room,
كل اسبوع في غرفة الاولاد
until one teacher saved my life.
حتى انقذت حياتي معلمة.
She saved my life by letting me go to the bathroom
اتقذت حياتي بأن سمحت لي بالذهاب الى دورة المياه
in the teachers' lounge.
في استراحة المعلمين.
She did it in secret.
فعلت ذلك سرا,
She did it for three years.
فعلت ذلك طوال ثلاثة سنين,
And I had to get out of town.
وكان علي مغادرة المدينة.
I had a thumb, I had 85 dollars,
كان لديّ فرصة, و لديّ 85$
and I ended up in San Francisco, California --
وانتهى بي الحال في سان فرانسيسكو,كاليفورنيا --
met a lover --
قابلت شريكا --
and back in the '80s, found it necessary
وفي الثمانينات, شعرت انه من الضروري
to begin work on AIDS organizations.
بدأ العمل في منظمات الايدز.
About three or four years ago,
قبل ثلاثة او اربعة اعوام,
I got a phone call in the middle of the night
تلقيت اتصالا في منتصف الليل
from that teacher, Mrs. Posten,
من المعلمة , السيدة بوستين
who said, "I need to see you.
التي قالت, " اريد مقابلتك.
I'm disappointed
اشعر بخيبة امل
that we never got to know each other as adults.
انه لم يكن لدينا الفرصة لنتعارف كبالغين.
Could you please come to Ohio,
رجاء هل بامكانك الحضور الى اوهايو,
and please bring that man
وارجوك احضر معك ذلك الرجل
that I know you have found by now.
الذي اعلم انك وجدته
And I should mention
واريد ان اذكر
that I have pancreatic cancer,
انني مصابة بسرطان البنكرياس,
and I'd like you to please
وارجوك ان تكون
be quick about this."
سريعا بهذا الخصوص."
Well, the next day we were in Cleveland.
حسنا,في اليوم التالي كنا في كليفلاند.
We took a look at her, we laughed, we cried,
القينا نظرة عليها, ضحكنا , وبكينا,
and we knew that she needed to be in a hospice.
وعلمنا انها في حاجة للانتقال الى نزل.
We found her one, we got her there,
وجدنا لها مكانا ونقلناها الى هناك,
and we took care of her
واعتنينا بها
and watched over her family,
وايضا تابعنا عائلتها,
because it was necessary.
لان ذلك كان ضروريا,
It's something we knew how to do.
وكان شيئا عرفنا كيف نقوم به.
And just as the woman who wanted to know me as an adult
وكأمرأة ارادت ان نتعارف كبالغين
got to know me,
تعرفت علي,
she turned into a box of ashes
تحولت الى صندوق من الرماد
and was placed in my hands.
تم وضعه بين يدي.
And what had happened
والذي حصل
was the circle had closed,
ان الدائرة تم اغلاقها,
it had become a circle --
اصبحت دائرة--
and that epiphany I talked about
وذلك الادراك الشيء الذي تحدثت عنه
presented itself.
هاهو يقدم نفسه
The epiphany is
ادراك الحقيقة هو
that death is a part of life.
ان الموت جزء من الحياة.
She saved my life;
هي أنقذت حياتي,
I and my partner saved hers.
وصديقي أنقذ حياتها.
And you know, that part of life needs everything
وكما تعلمون,ذلك الجزء من الحياة يحتاج كل الاشياء
that the rest of life does.
التي تحتاجها بقية الحياة
It needs truth and beauty,
يحتاج الصدق والجمال,
and I'm so happy it's been mentioned so much here today.
وانا سعيد ان ذلك ذكر هنا كثيرا هذا اليوم,
It also needs --
وايضا يحتاج--
it needs dignity,
يحتاج الكرامة,
love and pleasure,
الحب والسعادة.
and it's our job to hand those things out.
وهذه وظيفتنا ان نوصل هذه الامور للاخرين.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)